Matthew Lee

Phone +64 22 010 6288 | Email matthewleenz@yahoo.co.nz | Web mattlee68.github.io

About Me

I'm looking for a professional internship in a software development role to further develop my knowledge and experience in the IT sector. Ideally, this role would be in software development sector however I also have a keen interest in web development and UX. I'm passionate about the tech industry and am always dedicated to the task at hand. I have excellent communication and time-management skills. This is evidenced by working in multiple groups at university and working in a team environment in retail for the past three years all while juggling assignments and extra-curricular activities. If I'm not at my computer, you'll likely find me exploring the hills around Wellington or off travelling somewhere around New Zealand. Currently, I'm a third-year software engineering student at Victoria University of Wellington looking to complete my degree in November 2018.

Technical Skills

Area	Tools	Skill Level	Experience
Design	Photoshop, InDesign	Intermediate	Worked with these for projects
			throughout college and for personal use.
Programming	C, C++, Ruby on Rails,	Beginner	Learnt the basics in courses at university
Languages	HAML, SASS		(first and second year).
	HTML, CSS/SASS,	Intermediate	Developed websites throughout college
	Javascript, JQuery,		and university, as well as for hobbies.
	Python		
	Java	Proficient	Three years of learning Java at University
			for projects and assignments.
Version Control	Git	Beginner	Used throughout university for various
			projects.

Past Projects

Advance Directives Application

March 2017 – October 2017

Myself and five other third year students are developing an Advance Directives Application for a client who is a paramedic with Wellington Free Ambulance. This project requires a vast amount of project management whilst also considering the legal and ethical obligations of users. For this project, I held the role of developer.

Music Collection Database

October 2016

Using Ruby on Rails, I created a web based application to store details about a user's music collection. This involved managing and developing associated models, views and controllers. Languages and tools learnt for this project include HAML, SASS, Bootstrap and HTML5 Boilerplate. The application can be viewed on my GitHub (https://github.com/mattlee68/MusicCollection).

Education

Academic transcripts are available on request.

Victoria University of Wellington

February 2015 – November 2018

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours)

Achieved an A+ mark in most of my papers and currently have a GPA of A+. My lowest mark in my first three years of University is an A-. Academic highlights include achieving an A+ in three out of four of my second-year papers and two A+ grades in my trimester one third year papers.

University of Surrey, Guildford, United Kingdom

September 2016 – February 2017

International Exchange, Computing

As part of the Victoria Abroad program, I was accepted to be a part of an exchange for a trimester to the University of Surrey. Surrey is consistently ranked in the top 10 universities in the UK and specialises in sciences and engineering. I achieved firsts in all modules I was enrolled in.

Achievements & Volunteer Work

Dean's List, Faculty of Engineering and Computer Science

2015

The Dean's List is a formal and published record of students who achieve academic excellence in their current year of study in an undergraduate degree programme.

Onslow College Peer Support Leader

2014

Peer Support ensures students transitioning from intermediate can cope with college life. Peer Supporters are selected based on their skills in leadership, communication and cooperation, empathy and understanding and creativity and initiative.

Work Experience

Wisebuys on Dixon

May 2013 – Current

www.wisebuys.nz

Sales Assistant

My tasks involve interacting with customers to ensure they have a pleasant retail experience. I am also responsible for opening/closing the store occasionally on weekends as well as managing the social media channels.

Victoria University of Wellington

February 2016 – September 2016

www.victoria.ac.nz

ENGR101 Tutor & PHYS122/SARC122 Sessional Assistant (Marker)

My tasks included running labs, marking assignments/tests and making sure first year students knew the concepts and content being covered in this introductory engineering course. The PHYS122 and SARC122 courses involved marking assignments where I reported directly to the course coordinator.